Guide to Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Assorted Maps and Atlases, 1830-1990 AIS.Maps
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Assorted Maps and Atlases
1788-1990
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Archives Service Center
AIS.Maps
734 items (50 map case folders, 6 rolls, 95 volumes)
This finding aid lists the maps and atlases found in the Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) at the Archives Service Center that are not associated with any particular collection. The maps are mainly of Pittsburgh, Allegheny County and the southwestern Pennsylvania region. The atlases mostly include Sanborn maps, Hopkins plat books, atlases of the city of Pittsburgh and environs and of counties in Pennsylvania. Digital reproductions of some of the maps are available online.
Previous Citation
Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Assorted Maps and Atlases, 1830-1990, AIS.Maps, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into seven series:
Series I. City of Pittsburgh, 1830-1990
Series II. City of Pittsburgh Department of City Planning Maps of Pittsburgh, 1985-1987
Series III. Municipalities in Allegheny County, 1873-1965
Series IV. Allegheny County, 1946-1975
Series V. Other Pennsylvania Counties, 1916-1946
Series VI. Pennsylvania, 1896-1976
Series VII. Atlases
Scope and Content Notes
This finding aid lists the various maps and atlases housed in the Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) at the Archives Service Center that are not associated with any particular collection. The maps primarily cover Pittsburgh, Allegheny County and the southwestern Pennsylvania region and include, but are not limited to, maps of highways, boroughs, townships, counties, zoning districts, election districts, census tracts and property lots. Also included are a set of aerial photographs of the City of Pittsburgh. The atlases include Sanborn maps, Hopkins plat books, atlases of the City of Pittsburgh and environs and of counties in Pennsylvania. Note that the Historic Pittsburgh website provides online access to all of the published Hopkins plates for Pittsburgh.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of some of the maps are available online.
Pennsylvania, Southwestern -- Maps; Allegheny County (Pa.) -- Maps; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Maps; Pennsylvania -- Maps
- City of Pittsburgh, 1830-1990; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains maps of the City of Pittsburgh and its immediate environs. Similar maps may be found online in the Darlington Digital Library Maps website.
  - Maps of wards of Pittsburgh, showing election districts as established at no. 44 November Sessions, 1929, Wards 1-18, 20-24, 26, 28-32, 1930; 33 items (Map-case 8-12, Folder 2)
    - Ward 1
    - Ward 2
    - Ward 3
    - Ward 4
    - Ward 5
    - Ward 6
    - Ward 7
    - Ward 8
    - Ward 9
    - Ward 10
    - Ward 11
    - Ward 12
    - Ward 13
    - Ward 14, 1929 Election Districts
    - Ward 14, 1929 Election Districts, Colorized
    - Ward 14, 1937 Districts
    - Ward 15
    - Ward 16
    - Ward 17
    - Ward 18
    - Ward 20
    - Ward 21
    - Ward 22
    - Ward 23
    - Ward 24
    - Ward 26
    - Ward 28
    - Ward 29
    - Ward 30
    - Ward 31
    - Ward 32
  - Map of Pittsburgh and environs, from official records, original plat and actual surveys, published by R. L. Polk & Co., with Pittsburgh Street Guide on verso, 1916 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Downtown Pittsburgh, the Golden Triangle, 1955 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Photostat of Map of parts of the cities of Pittsburgh and Allegheny, showing railroads entering the same and the location of the Pennsylvania Canal as it was while in use, 1896 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Cram's map of the Golden Triangle, showing hotels, theatres, office buildings, railroad stations, etc. Engraved, printed and published by George F. Cram Co., ca. 1950 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Reprint of Map of Pittsburgh and its environs, surveyed and published by Jean Barbeau and Lewis Keyon; engraved by N. B. Molinoux, 1830 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Pittsburgh census tracts laid out for the Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce by G. A. Lundberg and F. F. Stephan and adopted by the Bureau of the Census for the 1930 Census of Population, 1931 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Rand-McNally new commercial atlas map of Pittsburgh, ca. 1905 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 7)
  - Maps of Allegheny County and the City of Pittsburgh, showing location of Catholic schools and including a list of Catholic colleges in Pennsylvania, ca. 1970 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 8)
  - Champion map of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania and vicinity, ca. 1974 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 9)
  - Map of Pittsburgh and vicinity, showing the location of the proposed subway with terminal points in Wilkinsburg and McKinley Park, ca. 1910 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 10)
  - City of Pittsburgh interim land use plan, prepared by the Pittsburgh Department of City Planning, 1963 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 3, Item 11)
  - Map of the City of Pittsburgh, Bicentennial edition, published by the Pittsburgh Dept. of City Planning, 1958 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Map of the City of Pittsburgh, published by the Pittsburgh Dept. of City Planning, 1969 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - City of Pittsburgh zoning district map, published by the Pittsburgh Dept. of City Planning, 1967 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - Photostat of Map of City of Pittsburgh wards and voting districts, including and inset map of Fort Pitt, ca. 1929; 3 items (Map-case 8-12, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - City of Pittsburgh voting districts and ward map, 1969; 4 items (Map-case 8-12, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - City of Pittsburgh ward map, prepared by the Pittsburgh Department of City Planning, 1969 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Business advertisement map of Brookline and Dormont, published by Creative Design and Marketing, 1990 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 6)
  - City of Pittsburgh zone map, 1927; 4 items (Map-case 8-12, Folder 7)
  - Plan of lots on Smithfield Farm, Pitt Township, on Pennsylvania Avenue, ca. 1860 (Map-case 8-12, Folder 8)
  - City of Pittsburgh and vicinity [from the CONSOL Energy Inc. Mine Maps and Records, AIS.1991.16], 1912 (Roll 307A)
  - Hearne Brothers Official Polyconic Projection Map of Greater Pittsburgh, undated (Roll 3)
  - Map of Pittsburgh, with relief shown by contour lines and spot heights, prepared by the Pittsburgh Department of City Planning, undated (Roll 5)
  - Interim thoroughfare plan, prepared by the Pittsburgh Department of City Planning, undated
  - Map of 1960 census tracts, prepared by the Pittsburgh Department of City Planning, undated
  - Map of existing highway network, prepared by the Pittsburgh Department of City Planning, 1963
  - Plan showing location of mains and ditribution pipe, City of Allegheny (now the North side), 1876 (Roll 5, Folder 9)
  - Sewerage Map of the City of Allegheny (now North Side), 1881 (Roll 5, Folder 10)
  - Pittsburgh Regional Planning Association, Downtown Pittsburgh, Proposed Projects, 1951 (Roll 5, Folder 11)
  - "This is the New Pittsburgh Renaissance City of America, Map with Visitors Guide", c. 1970 (Roll 5, Folder 12)
  - "Souvenir of Metropolitan Pittsburgh, Pa. Map showing the location of some Points of Interest", c 1960 (Roll 5, Folder 13)
- City of Pittsburgh Department of City Planning maps of Pittsburgh, 1985-1987; II.
  This series contains maps and aerial photographs created by the City of Pittsburgh Department of City Planning and is further divided into three subseries: 1. Aerial Photographs; 2. Topography; and 3. Parcels.
  - Aerial Photographs, 1.
    - Key map and sheets 1-20, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 1)
    - Sheets 21-40, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 2)
    - Sheets 41-60, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 3)
    - Sheets 61-64,66-72, 74-80, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 4)
    - Sheets 81-97, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 5)
    - Sheets 104-108, 113-116, 119-120, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 6)
    - Sheets 121-129, 131-135, 137-140, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 7)
    - Sheets 161-163, 167, 170-178, 184-186, 190, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 8)
    - Sheets 225-228, 231-232, 234, 243, 289, 296-298, 1985 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 9)
  - Topography, 2.
    - Key map and sheets 1-20, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 10)
    - Sheets 21-36, 39-40, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 11)
    - Sheets 41-60, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 12)
    - Sheets 61-64, 66-72, 75-80, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 13)
    - Sheets 81-97, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 14)
    - Sheets 104, 106-108, 113-116, 119-129, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 15)
    - Sheets 131-135, 137-139, 162-163, 170-172, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 16)
    - Sheets 173-178, 184-186, 190, 231-232, 243, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 17)
  - Parcels, 3.
    - Key map and sheets 1-20, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 18)
    - Sheets 21-36, 39-40, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 19)
    - Sheets 41-60, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 20)
    - Sheets 61-64, 66-72, 75-80, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 21)
    - Sheets 81-97, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 22)
    - Sheets 104, 106-108, 113-116, 119-129, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 23)
    - Sheets 131-135, 137-139, 162-163, 170-172, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 24)
    - Sheets 173-178, 184-186, 190, 231-232, 243, 1987 (Map-case 12-5, Folder 25)
- Municipalities in Allegheny County, 1873-1965; III.
  This series contains maps of individual boroughs and townships in Allegheny County, arranged alphabetically.
  - Zoning map of the Township of Bethel, Allegheny County, Pa., ca. 1940 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Borough of Blawnox, O'Hara Township, Allegheny County, Penna., 1926 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - Brackenridge Borough, showing election districts at No. 44 Nov. Sessions, 1929, 40th Senatorial District, 13th L. E. District, 33rd Congressional District, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Braddock index map, ca. 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Braddock Hills Borough index map, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Clairton index map, reduced and traced by John Marcy, 1938 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Collier Township index map, drawn by W. Russell, traced by C. A. Greenwalt, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Coraopolis Borough, 1970 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 8)
  - Crafton, traced and drawn by J. M. Andrews, 1938 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 9)
  - Crescent Township, 2 precincts, 11th L. E. District, ca. 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 1, Item 10)
  - East Deer Township index map, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - East Deer Township, 13th L. E. District, ca. 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - Zone map, Borough of Edgewood, Pa., accompanying the zoning ordinance of the Borough of Edgewood, approved the 6th day of April 1925, 1931 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Elizabeth Township, showing the election districts at no. 44 Nov. Sessions, 1929, 10th L. E. District, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - Elizabeth Township, 10th L. E. District, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - Elizabeth Township index map, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Zoning map of Emsworth Borough, 1931 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 7)
  - Fawn Township index map, drawn by J. Schutzman, traced by H. C. McKee, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 8)
  - Findlay Township, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 9)
  - Forward Township, 10th L. E. District, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 10)
  - Borough of Fox Chapel, 1933 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 11)
  - Frazier Township index map, drawn by J. Schutzman, traced by H. C. McKee, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 2, Item 12)
  - Hampton Township, 12th L. E. District, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Harmar Township, showing election districts at no. 44 Nov. Sessions 1929, 12th L. E. District (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Harmar Township index map, drawn by J. Schutzman and traced by N. A. Barnhart, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Harrison Township index map, drawn by J. Schutzman and traced by N. A. Barnhart, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Homestead district map, ca. 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Homestead and West Homestead map, reduced and traced by Paul Sibery, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Homestead index map, ca. 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 7)
  - Map of Homestead, by W. W. Smith, unknown (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 8)
  - Indiana Township index map, drawn by J. Schutzman and traced by H. C. McKee, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 9)
  - Jefferson Township index map, drawn by William Russell and traced by H. C. McKee, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 10)
  - Kennedy Township map, unknown (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 11)
  - Lincoln Township, 10th L. E. District, ca. 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 12)
  - Lincoln Township index map, traced by A. Kloss, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 3, Item 13)
  - McCandless Township index map, traced by C. P. Stroech, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - City of McKeesport, Pennsylvania map, prepared by American Air Surveys, Inc., ca. 1950 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - City map and street guide of McKeesport, Pennsylvania, prepared by the McKeesport Chamber of Commerce, ca. 1940 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - City map and street guide of McKeesport, Pennsylvania, prepared by the McKeesport Chamber of Commerce, ca. 1955 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - Marshall Township plat map, unknown (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - Alteration of township line between Moon and Crescent Township, no. 67 April Sessions 1924, Allegheny County Engineer's Office (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 6)
  - Moon Township index map, drawn by J. Sandulak and traced by G. Gloekler, ca. 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 7)
  - Map of the Township of Mount Lebanon, Allegheny County, Pa., 1939 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 8)
  - Mount Lebanon index map, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 9)
  - Neville Township, 1914 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 10)
  - North Fayette Township zoning map, compiled by Earl E. Gallagher, 1955 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 11)
  - North Fayette Township, unknown (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 12)
  - North Versailles Township, 10th L. E. District, 1934 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 13)
  - North Versailles Township index map, traced by A. Kloss, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 14)
  - Plan of Township of North Versailles, 1948 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 4, Item 15)
  - O'Hara Township index map, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Ohio Township index map, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Penn Township index map, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Pine Township plat map, 1921 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - Pine Township map M-P-Q, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - Plat map showing proposed area for incorporation into Borough of Pleasant Hills, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 6)
  - Rankin index map, ca. 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 7)
  - Reserve Township index map, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 8)
  - Richland Township index map, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 9)
  - Robinson Township index map, ca. 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 10)
  - Robinson Township, showing election districts at no. 44 Nov. Sessions 1929, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 11)
  - Rosslyn Farms Borough, sheet A and index map, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 5, Item 12)
  - Scott Township index map, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - Township of Scott, 1954 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - Shaler Township index map, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - Plan of the Borough of Sharpsburg, 1945 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 4)
  - South Fayette Township plat map, 1935 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 5)
  - Springdale Borough index map, ca. 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 6)
  - Springdale Township plat map, ca. 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 7)
  - Springdale Township index map, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 8)
  - Stowe Township index map, 1938 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 9)
  - Stowe Township, 11th L. E. District, 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 10)
  - Swissvale index map, 1938 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 11)
  - Swissvale Borough voting districts, 1942 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 12)
  - Swissvale Borough index map, block and lot system, ca. 1952 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 13)
  - Thornburg Borough plan map, reduced by Roy M. Harrah, 1937 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 6, Item 14)
  - Map of Township of Upper St. Clair, 1952 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - Plat map of Upper St. Clair Township, ca. 1945 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 2)
  - Map of 251 lots at Verner on the Allegheny Valley Rail Road, 2 1/2 miles from the city line, laid out for Col. Wm. Phillips, unknown (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 3)
  - Plan of lots situated in the Borough of Verona, laid out by Col. William Phillips, 1873 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 4)
  - Plan of partition of lands [in Verona] of James Verner, Thomas A. Scott and others made at No. 361 of January Term 1880 Court of Common Pleas Number Two (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 5)
  - Plan of Versailles Township, traced from official records, 1948 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 6)
  - Map of Wall Borough, drawn and traced by G. L. Bailey, 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 7)
  - West Deer Township, showing precincts for 12th L. E. District, ca. 1930 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 8)
  - West Elizabeth index map, traced by Clarence Weinzierl, 1935 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 9)
  - West Homestead index map, drawn by J. Schutzman, ca. 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 10)
  - Map of proposed park areas, Project 90, West Mifflin Borough, 1965 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 11)
  - West View index map, ca. 1936 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 12)
  - Plan of the Borough of Wilkinsburg, 1952 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 13)
  - Wilkinsburg Borough map, drawn and traced by J. E. Sandulak, 1938 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 14)
  - Wilkinsburg Borough index map, drawn and traced by S. J. Patterson, ca. 1935 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 7, Item 15)
- Allegheny County, 1946-1975; IV.
  This series contains maps of Allegheny County as a whole. Similar maps may be found online in the Darlington Digital Library Maps website.
  - Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1952 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1959 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1963 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 4)
  - Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1968 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 5)
  - Reduced copy of Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1968 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 6)
  - Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1971 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 7)
  - Road map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the County Planning Commission, 1975 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 8)
  - Map of Allegheny County, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 9)
  - Allegheny County minor civil divisions, with Congressional Districts outlined, 1962 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 10)
  - Port Authority Transit system map, Spring 1976 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 11)
  - Map of Monongahela River Thru-Way Project, with accompanying notes, 1964 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 8, Item 12)
  - General highway map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1964 (Map-case 30-7, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Map of Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, from actual surveys by S. N. and F. W. Beers, 1862 (Roll 1)
  - Official Hearne Brothers polyconic projection map of North Pittsburgh and northern half of Allegheny County, undated (Roll 2)
- Other Pennsylvania Municipalities and Counties, 1890-1946; V.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains maps of other counties in southwestern Pennsylvania.
  - Connected draft of the 45 "out lots" of the town of Beaver, 1890 (Roll 6)
  - Map of Armstrong County, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - Map of Beaver County, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 9, Item 2)
  - Map of Butler County, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 9, Item 3)
  - Map of Fayette County, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 9, Item 4)
  - Map of Greene County, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 9, Item 5)
  - Map of the public roads in Indiana County, Pennsylvania, constructed from actual surveys made under the direction of the State Highway Department, 1916 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 9, Item 6)
  - Map of Washington County, prepared by the Pennsylvania Department of Highways, 1946 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 9, Item 7)
- Pennsylvania, 1896-1976; VI.
  This series contains maps of Pennsylvania as a whole, as well as maps of specific areas within Pennsylvania not covered by other series. Similar maps may be found online in the Darlington Digital Library Maps website.
  - Photocopy of Relief map of the Allegheny Mountains between Johnstown, Altoona and Hollidaysburg, 1896 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - Map of the southwestern area of Pennsylvania, 1749-1799, commissioned for the people of western Pennsylvania in honor of our nation's Bicentennial Celebration by Pittsburgh National Bank, with historical facts and notes developed by Robert C. Alberts, 1975 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 10, Item 2)
  - Bird's eye view map of Mount Pleasant, Pennsylvania in 1900, 1976 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - Pennsylvania Scenic and Historic Commission map, circa 1935 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - Pennsylvania, showing counties, cities, towns, villages, railroads (steam and electric), circa 1941 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 11, Item 2)
  - Road map of Pennsylvania, published by the State Highway Department, showing state highways, 1916 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 11, Item 3)
  - State Forest map of Pennsylvania, with state highways, state parks, normal schools, game preserves, resources, important frontier forts, etc., issues by the Department of Forestry, 1922 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 11, Item 4)
  - Frontier forts of Pennsylvania (after William A. Hunter), by D. Macfarlan, 1956-08-01T00:00:00+00:00 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 11, Item 5)
- Other U.S. Locations, 1848-1935; VII.
  - United States Domestic Air Mail System, 1935 (Map-case 8-13, Folder 11)
  - Map of the United States, from the latest authorities, published in New York by Ensigns & Thayer, 1848 (Map-case 30-1, Folder 1)
  - Old trails and routes in the United States, by Earl Gurney Mead, 1965 (Map-case 30-1, Folder 2)
  - Office of the Geographer, Department of State, Steel Production, 1870, 1913 and 1939, c1940 (Map-case 30-1, Folder 3)
- Atlases, 1788-1990; VIII.
  This series contains atlases of Pittsburgh, Allegheny County and other counties in Pennsylvania, as well as of Pennsylvania and neighboring states. It is divided into five subseries: 1. Sanborn Maps; 2. Hopkins Plat Books and Atlases; 3. Other Pittsburgh Atlases; 4. Pennsylvania Counties; and 5. Pennsylvania and Other States.
  - Sanborn Maps, 1.
    - McKeesport, Pa., 1904 (Shelf 1/1/1)